I am Moon brother two mice fell into a bucket of cream first quickly gave up and drowned
两只老鼠掉进了一桶奶油中 第一只很快就放弃 然后淹死了
The second mouse struggled until he churned the cream into butter and climbed out of the bucket alive. I was the second mouse. The man who said this was a successful businessman
第二只却一直努力挣扎着 最终他把奶油搅成了黄油 然后爬出奶桶 活了下来 我就是那第二只老鼠 说这话的人是一个成功的商人
He's speaking at an elite club in New York that only accepts America's top elite and he's the 58th member
此时他正在纽约一个精英俱乐部演讲 这个俱乐部只接受美国顶尖的精英人士 而他是第58个社员
In the audience, his son Frank warmly applauds his father with adoring eyes, but in fact Frank's father is a liar
台下 他的儿子弗兰克热烈的为父亲鼓掌 满脸都是崇拜的目光 但其实弗兰克的父亲是个满嘴谎言的家伙
He can tell a lie like it's the truth and he's always got a way of getting people to trust him and he's got a new rule that the way to get people to respect you have to dress well
他能把谎话说的跟真的一样 而且他总有办法获得别人的信任 他新风一条禁律 要想获得别人的尊重 先要穿的光鲜两粒
With this skill he managed to slip into high society and marry Frank's mother a demure blonde
靠着这种忽悠技能 他成功的混入了上流社会 还娶到了弗兰克的母亲 一个温柔端庄的金发美人
But it wasn't long before Frank's father tried to keep you out of business because of tax problems and no major bank would lend to him
然而 人生无常不久 弗兰克的父亲就因为税务问题避您破产 各大银行都不愿意贷款给他
The family sold the villa to move into a shabby apartment and Frank transferred to a public school. Frank was mocked by the students as a substitute teacher when he entered the classroom in his uniform, so he pretended to be a teacher. He not only corrected the students who laughed at him, but he was afraid that the substitute teacher would send him away
一家人卖掉别墅 搬进了破旧的公寓 弗兰克也转到了一所公立学校 瑞 弗兰克穿着制服 一进教室 就被学生们嘲笑是代课老师 于是他索性就冒充起了老师 不仅把嘲笑他的同学修理了一顿 害怕真的代课老师打发走了
It took a week for his ploy to be discovered. Instead of scolding him, his father gave his son a bloody look of approval when he returned home yesterday to find a man in his house
一周后 他的小伎俩才被识破 父亲得知后不仅没有责骂他 还用沾血的目光对儿子的行为表示认可 昨天回家后 弗兰克发现家里出现了一个男人
Having been under the influence of his father for a long time, Frank seemed to have a preternatural sensitivity to lies. He immediately saw the secret between his mother and a man and a few days later his speculation was confirmed
由于长期受父亲的影响 弗兰克对于谎言似乎有着超乎常人的敏感 他一下子就看出了母亲和男人之间的秘密 几天后 他的猜测便得到了证实
His parents are in the process of getting a divorce and they're asking him to sign the divorce papers to choose whether to live with his father or his mother and they're trying to keep a cool face
父母正在办理离婚手续 并让他在离婚协议上签字 选择是跟父亲生活还是跟母亲生活 父母都极力装出一副云淡风轻的样子
But Frank couldn't take it. He rushed out of his house and ran down the street desperate. He didn't want to go home but he couldn't go anywhere because he had no money
但弗兰克却无法接受 他冲出家门 不顾一切的在大街上狂奔 他不想回家 但由于没钱 哪都去不了
Then he remembered the airdrop check his father gave him and tried to get cash through fraud. He cheated money with the means he learned from his father, but he could not gain others' trust due to his immature technology
于是他想起了父亲给他的空投支票 想通过造假套取现金 他用从父亲那里学来的手段骗钱 但由于技术不成熟 并不能获取别人的信任
He didn't get a penny for Frank's loss. Walking down the street in the middle of the street were a bunch of uniformed pilots and stewardesses
他一分钱也没捞到 弗兰克失落的走在大街上 中间的一群穿着制服的飞行员和空姐 他们风光无限 孩子们冲到机长面前所要签名
As if inspired, Frank disguised himself as a student journalist and interviewed the pilot, obtained a series of professional information about Van Mae Airlines, and then managed to get a first officer's outfit and credentials. He remembered his father had said that an honest man had nothing to fear
弗兰克仿佛受到了启发 他伪装成学生 记者采访机长 获得了一系列范美航空公司的专业资料 随后又小时手段钻控制 搞到了一身副机长的行头和证件 他记得父亲曾说过 一个老实人没有什么好害怕的
So he tried not to be afraid to walk down the street with his head held high and then he forged a bunch of airline checks on his model plane and cashed them in and people smiled at him all the way
所以他尽量让自己不害怕 昂首挺胸的走在大街上 随后私下飞机模型上的航标伪造了一大堆的航空专用支票再去套现时 人们对他已是笑脸相宜 一路绿灯
Your level of trust depends on the clothes you wear and your credentials. Then he gets on the plane disguised as an airplane pilot, goes to the pilot yard and brags with the temporary captain. Then he gets a stewardess and catches him the way dad used to do. Then he gets a license and then he uses the bar with the bank teller
你的颗信任度取决于你身上所穿的衣服以及你的证件 接着他有伪装成飞机师登上飞机 先是跑到驾驶场和临时机长吹吹牛 熟落熟落 再找个空姐用父亲经常用的那招俘获他 然后再来个机证 随后利用和银行出纳条形的功夫
After learning about check printing, he went to an auction and bought a check coding machine. In the 1960s, the security system of American banks was not perfect. Frank, who was good at controlling, went on a crime spree and kept a lot of money in his pocket
了解到了支票印刷的相关事项 在接着去拍卖会买了台支票编码机 60年代的美国银行安全体系还不完善 善于专控制的弗兰克疯狂作案 大把钞票留进他的口袋 与此同时 他写信告诉父亲自己当上了发美航空的副机长 还送给父亲一辆名贵的敞篷车 他希望父亲的吗
The mother took it home and the father said with tears in his eyes that the mother was very stubborn and did not want to come back
母亲接回家 父亲含着眼泪说 母亲很固执 不想回来 老鼠兴风作浪 不断投凉 终于引起了猫儿的注意
Fbi agent Carl was in charge of the case and he tracked Frank down to the hotel after he figured out his pattern
联邦调查局的探员卡尔负责此事案件 他案中摸清了弗兰克的作案规律后 一路追到了他 落脚了酒店
Frank doesn't even know he's in trouble and greets his neighbors on the way up the stairs when Carl breaks down the door with a gun
而此时的弗兰克还没意识到自己有了麻烦 上楼时还热情的跟邻居父子打招呼 当卡尔举着枪破门而入时
He can't help but walk out of the bathroom with his face poised and his brain racing as he claims to be a Secret Service officer
他不禁不慢的走出卫生间 面部改设镇定直弱 此时的他大脑飞速转动 他谎称自己是特勤局的警员
He ended up with the same suspect who said that Carl was a little late and that he and Patang had apprehended the suspect and then handed Carl his identification wallet
和卡尔最终的是同一个嫌犯 他说卡尔来晚了一步 他和帕当已经抓捕了嫌犯 随后把自己的证件钱包递给了卡尔
And let Carl see the scene of the escort downstairs that father and son became the props of his lie a lie is more flowing than the truth
又让卡尔看楼下的押解场景 那对父子成了他谎言的道具一番谎话说的行云流水 比真话还真
Then he picked up Bemagee and the check and said I'm going to get this down and then he walked out and waited for Frank to leave before Carl realized he opened his wallet and found a pile of broken paper
接着他抱起别马吉和支票 说 我先把这些物证搬下去 然后就大摇大摆的走了出去 等弗兰克走后 卡尔才反应过来 打开钱包看到的是一堆烂纸片
By this time, Frank is already gone. Frank learns that he has made headlines in the newspaper and is called the James Bond of the Air. So he simply orders himself a Bond suit and buys the same sports car and goes on his epic journey in this image
此时弗兰克已经走远了 弗兰克得知自己登上了报纸头条 还被称为空中詹姆斯 邦德 于是他索性就给自己定做了一套邦德西服 还购买了同款跑车 并以这样的形象开展了他的烈焰之旅 时间一晃到了圣诞夜 离婚后独居的卡尔主动要求到警局职业班
To his surprise, Frank called to ask after him and unapologetically revealed his heart, but Carl did not believe that Carl was aware of Frank's loneliness
出乎意料的是 弗兰克竟打电话来问候他 还有时无孔地透露了自己的心中 可卡尔并不相信卡尔意识到了弗兰克的孤独
He said you just don't have anyone to talk to. Frank hung up the phone with a snap and then Caldron told the waiter
他说 你只是找不到人聊天 弗兰克听把啪的一声挂掉了电话 随后卡尔通服务员口中得知
Frank's pseudonyms are all derived from the comic book character's realization that Frank is probably a minor
弗兰克所用的假名都来自于漫画人物 恍然大悟的他这才意识到弗兰克很可能还是个未成年的孩子
Since Frank mentioned the New York baseball team on the phone, he targeted young runaways in New York City
由于弗兰克在打电话时提到过纽约的棒球队 于是他把目标锁定在纽约市离家出走的年轻人
And began to gradually investigate the efforts paid off Carl found Frank's mother support Carl finally locked the identity of the suspect
并开始逐步排查 功夫不负有心人 卡尔找到了弗兰克的母亲支持 卡尔终于锁定了嫌犯的身份
When she learned that her son had faked the missing ticket, her mother rushed to pay him back. Carl told him that Frank had cheated about $1.3 million so far
当得知儿子伪造失票骗钱后 母亲赶紧要拿钱替他还上 卡尔告诉他目前为止弗兰克已骗取约130万美元
My mother was stunned while Frank was partying and drinking and having a good time when a friend fell and went to the hospital
母亲顿时傻了眼 而此时弗兰克正在举行派对 花天酒地逍遥快活 这是一个朋友摔伤被送进医院
Frank rushed to visit a little nurse who was scolded and cried by the doctor. Frank quickly comforted him when he learned in small talk that the nurse with braces was named Brenda. After a soft shower of comfort, the little nurse finally broke his seat and smiled He surrounded Harvard
弗兰克赶去探望 刚好碰到一个被医生骂哭的小护士 弗兰克连忙安慰他 闲聊中得知这个带着牙套的小护士名叫布兰达 一番柔身细雨的安抚后 小护士终于破席微笑 此时的弗兰克再次玩心大发 决定过一把当医生的隐 顺便把妹 凭借着高超的造假技术 他围绕了哈佛
Wimpy from medical school made it through the interview process and became an emergency room supervisor on the night shift watching surgical videos in his spare time and catching up on medical stuff and Lant was all over the hospital
医学院的文皮顺利通过面试后 成为了一名夜班急诊室的主管 没事的时候就看看手术录像 恶补医学之事 兰特在医院里混的风声水起
No one doubted his identity after all, he didn't have to do a lot of things himself. He was more of a face-off for the hospital. Brenda was crazy in love with him and always looked for opportunities to get close to Frank
没有一个人怀疑他的身份 毕竟很多事情都不用他亲自上手 他更多的只是为医院撑个脸面 而布兰达更是疯狂的爱上了他 总是找机会接近弗兰克 弗兰克也不含糊 直接就亲上了 布兰达更是不甘示弱
After hearing that Brenda had been kicked out of the house by her parents because of abortion, Frank fell in love with the girl who had similar experience with him. The two loved her most and completed the sublimation of love. Frank wanted to settle down for the first time
得知布兰达因为堕胎被父母赶出家门 呼声流落在外后 弗兰克对这个和自己有着类似经历的姑娘心生两爱 动了真心 两人最热爱和完成了爱情的升华 弗兰克第一次动了想要安定下来的念头
Carl was not idle at this time he was met by Frank's father and learned Frank's address from the letters between him and his son
此时的卡尔也没闲着 他遭到了弗兰克的父亲 并从他和儿子的来往信件中得知了弗兰克的地址
Maybe the place was long gone by the time Carl and his men arrived in a hurry and Frank was used to firing a bullet and moving the place
可能卡尔带人火急火燎的赶到时 这里早已人去楼空 弗兰克早已习惯了打一枪换一个地方
His heart was in the air and Carl was taking his time while Frank and Brenda were visiting his future in-laws
他心中飘忽不低 而卡尔每次都是慢慢拍 此时的弗兰克已经和布兰达一起登门拜访未来的岳父岳母了
At a family dinner, he bragged about passing the bar exam and was about to go back to his old job just in time to run into a gun. My father in law is a veteran prosecutor. What a coincidence to ask again
家庭宴会上 他吹嘘自己通过了司法考试 真打算干回老本行 随时刚好撞到枪口上 老丈人真是一个资深的检察官 再一问 真是巧了 他杜撰的毕业学校都和老丈人一样
Frank thought he was clever but in order to make one lie he had to kill more lies. His father in law had seen through his lies. After dinner he called Frank to his room
弗兰克自以为机智 可为了圆一个谎就得杀更多的谎 老丈人早已看穿了他的谎言 饭后 他将弗兰克叫到房间
Frank knew there was no way to hide everything he said I'm not a pilot or a doctor or a lawyer I'm just a young man who fell in love with your daughter
弗兰克知道无法在隐瞒砍成了一切 他说 我不是机长也不是医生 更不是律师 我只是一个爱上了你女儿的年轻人
The father-in-law did not blame him, but helped him pass the judicial examination in a week. In the evening, the family sat together and played the chorus with joy, warmth and happiness. When Frank saw his parents-in-law dancing together, the scene of deja veja when he saw love and grazing reminded him of his parents
老丈人并没有责怪他 反而帮助他在一周内就通过了司法考试 到了晚上 一家人坐在一起欢乐打合唱 温馨有幸福 从弗兰克看到岳父岳母在一起翩翩起舞 恩爱和牧时似曾相识的场景 让他想起了自己的父母 弗兰克回来趟家 复制相见后拥抱在一起
Frank invited his father to his engagement ball and said excitedly that he was now rich enough to buy back all the things he had lost
弗兰克邀请父亲去参加他的订婚舞会 他兴奋的说 他现在非常有钱 能把以前失去的东西全都买回来
He persuaded his father to try to win back his mother, but his father went to tell him that his mother had remarried and Frank's heart was heavy. All his efforts were to bring the family closer to Shigehara
他劝父亲试着去挽回母亲 但父亲去告诉了他母亲再婚的消息 听罢弗兰克心情沉重 他一切的努力就是想让这个家迫近重原
But it turned out to be an empty night and he left. Another Christmas Eve Frank called Carl again and this time he asked for peace. He told Carl that he was getting married and wanted to be quiet
但到头来却还是一场空 他头夜不回的离开了又是一个平安夜 弗兰克再次李卡尔打去了电话 而这一次是求和 他告诉卡尔他要结婚了 想安静下来
Chukal let him go, Carl says that the $4 million debt can't be let go, he must send Frank to prison. After hanging up the phone, Carl sends someone to investigate the mystery of the recent wedding. On the day of engagement, the family and friends gather together, but Carl comes with his team
丘卡尔放过他 卡尔却说400万美元的债不可能就这么算了 他一定要把弗兰克送进监狱 挂完电话后 卡尔派人着手调查近期的结婚之谜 到了订婚这天 亲朋好友齐聚一堂 卡尔却带着人马赶了过来
Radical Frank sensed something was wrong and dragged Brenda into the room while the police were talking to the crowd
激进的弗兰克察觉到异常 称警方和众人交涉之时 弗兰克一把将布兰达拽进了房间
He broke out boxes and boxes of money while he excitedly confessed everything to Brenda who had no idea what was going on
他一边爆出整箱整箱的钞票 一边激动的向布兰达坦白一切 可布兰达却一头雾水
I have no idea what he's talking about. It's too urgent to explain. Frank's supposed to meet him at the airport in two days
完全不知道他在说什么 听光紧急 来不及解释更多 弗兰克和他约定两天后在机场见面
By the time Carl got there Frank had already jumped and fled leaving Brenda where she was in shock and two days later Brenda showed up as promised
等卡尔赶到 弗兰克早已跳成逃跑 只留下惊魂未定的布兰达待在原地 两天后 布兰达如约而至
But instead of meeting him, Frank hides in his car and looks around and finds out that the police have already taken care of him
可弗兰克并没有贸然赴约 而是躲在车里观察周围情况 他发现警察已经布下天罗地王
So his heart gave birth to a plan to pick up their forged documents to put on the handsome uniform came to a university to recruit air hostesses a girl tell their own magic tell their excellent results show talent
于是他心生一计 拿起自己伪造的证件 穿上那套帅气逼人的制服 来到一所大学招募空姐 一个个女孩们各显神通 诉说了自己优异的成绩 展现才艺
Finally, he chose eight girls with long breasts and thighs and pretty faces. Then surrounded by the girls, it seems that the policemen who entered the airport were afraid to see a bunch of air hostesses who appeared out of thin air were already lured away. So Frank sneaked away in the eyes of the police
最后他选了胸大腿长 脸蛋好看的八个女孩 接着在女孩们的簇拥下似乎忌惮的走进机场 悟空的警察们见到一堆凭空出现的空姐 不是早就被勾走了 就这样 弗兰克在警察眼皮底下偷偷溜走了
At this time, Carl received a call from a colleague who said they found someone acting suspiciously. When they got to the front, the other person was just a soldier. There was a driver
此时的卡尔接到了同事的电话 说是发现了行迹可疑的人 等他们杀到跟前 对方却只是一个打仗 有个司机 这真是有人给了他100美元
Send him in his uniform to pick up a man who is Carl Carl again Seven months later Carl goes to the experts with the Frank family's goofy-ass new work and learns that the check might have been printed in France
让他穿着制服来接人 而要接的那个人正是卡尔 卡尔再次重击七个月后 卡尔带着弗兰克一家乱真的新作品去请教专家 得知支票有可能是在法国印制的
Thinking that Frank's mother was born in France, Carl immediately sets out to find out. But Carl arrives at the printing house. Franco is pushing away the list and printing the lost ticket in a frenzy
联想到弗兰克的母亲出生于法国 于是卡尔立即动身前去一探虚实 但卡尔赶到印刷厂 弗兰哥正甩开榜子 热火朝天的印着失票 见到卡尔弗兰克瞬间变得亢奋癫狂 然而他并不想束手就擒
He means you stole money from the French and the French already hate you for buying in
能想顾忌从事来个经常脱窍 他是说你偷了法国人的钱 法国人已经恨你入股
There's French cops all over the place and you'll be shot if you run out the door and Frank doesn't believe he's killed too many lies
外面全是法国警察 只要你逃出门就会被击毙 弗兰克却不相信他杀了太多谎
Can't tell the difference between a lie and a truth. Carl, are you telling the truth? Carl nods firmly. Frank finally relents. He is handcuffed and led away by the French police
已经分不清谎言和真实 他们 卡尔 你说的是真话吗 卡尔坚定的点了点头 弗兰克终于妥协 自己带上了手铐 随后便被法国警方带走
Carr promised to extradite him to the United States and after four years of relentless efforts he finally made good on his promise
卡尔承诺会将他引渡回美国 四年之后 经过不懈的努力 卡尔终于兑现了他的承诺
As the plane was about to land Frank asked to call his father, but Carl told Frank that one of his fathers had died unexpectedly
飞机即将落地时 弗兰克要求给父亲打电话 可卡尔却告诉弗兰克他父亲一位意外已经去世
Frank couldn't take it and locked himself in the bathroom until Carl sensed something was wrong and smashed the door only to find that Frank had disappeared
弗兰克无法接受情绪激动 把自己锁在卫生间里 等卡尔察觉到异常 撞开门后却发现弗兰克凭空消失了
On closer inspection, he saw that he had removed the handwashing table and got out. At the moment of landing, Frank climbed onto the landing gear and jumped out of the plane. He went to his mother's new house and saw a lovely little girl through the window
仔细一看才发现 他拆掉洗手台 钻出去了 飞机着陆的一瞬间 弗兰克爬上起落架 跳机后逃跑 他去了母亲的新家 透过窗户看见了一个可爱的小女孩
The little girl was born by Frank's mother after their marriage. Looking at the happy family together, Frank's eyes welled up with tears. The police came immediately
这个小女孩正是弗兰克的母亲 在婚后所生 看着他们一家人幸福的在一起 弗兰克的眼眶湿润了 警察随即赶了过来 不欲望眼前的一切 母亲近在眼前
He raised his hand slowly for the first time without a fight. While Frank was serving a 12-year sentence, Carl stumbled upon Frank's amazing administrative abilities
却又遥不可及 他缓缓地举起了手 这是他第一次没有反抗就放弃了 弗兰克被判12年刑期 服刑期间 卡尔无意中发现了弗兰克惊人的行政能力
Frank was officially recruited as an FBI agent with approval but he had to work under Carl's supervision and under control
于是经过批准后将弗兰克正式招募为联邦调查局的探员 但他必须在卡尔的监护下工作 接受管制
A few days after he went to work, he was restless again. He put on the captain's uniform and ran away again. Maybe he was used to seeing the sea as his home
随之上班没几天 他又不安分了 穿上机长制服后再次出逃 或许他早已习惯了视海为家 无拘无束的生活 然而卡尔却在最后时刻追上他说
Sometimes it's easier to live a lie and I'm going to let you go tonight because I know you'll be back on Monday and there's no one behind you anymore. And on Monday morning he waited and waited and waited for Frank
有时候 活在谎言里会比较容易 我今晚会放你走 因为我知道你周一就会回来 你后面已经没有人在追你了 周一早上 他而在忐忑不安的等待中终于盼回了弗兰克
Tollefrank married and had children and lived a quiet and happy life. He helped the police to solve a number of bank fraud cases and participated in the design of a variety of encrypted checks. He became a well-known expert in the industry and got high salaries from banks and major companies
托莱弗兰克结婚生子 一直过着平静幸福的生活 协助警方破获多起银行欺诈案并参与设计了多种加密支票 成为了业界知名的专家 得到了银行和各大公司的高薪聘请
The game of Cat and Mouse is also a 2002 Steven Spielberg film based on real time
猫鼠游戏也是史蒂芬斯皮尔伯格2002年上映的作品 电影根据真实时间改编
The original was Frank Abanel, the youngest international wanted man in the history of the fbi who was described by some as the greatest fraud artist of the 20th century according to historical records he impersonated no fewer than eight identities pilot teacher doctor warning lawyer and so on
原心是被誉为fbi有史以来年龄最小的跨国通缉犯弗兰克阿巴内尔 有人称他是20世纪最大的诈骗艺术家 据史料记载他至少冒充过不少于八个身份 飞行员 教师 医生 预警律师等等
He escaped from prison twice and all of this happened before he was 21 and Heira's life was a lonely one because you couldn't say the truth to anyone and this is the monologue that Abanel had when he was a child
还越狱过两次 而这些事情全都发生在他21岁之前 平安子的生活是孤独的 因为你不可以向任何人说真心话 这是阿巴内尔内心的独白 当他还是一个孩子的时候
He was acutely aware that there was a price to be paid for telling the truth and he knew that if it wasn't for the uniform and the badge
他就清醒的认识到说真话是要付出代价的 他也知道如果不是制服和证件
People don't think highly of you and you get hurt when you tell the truth and you get trust when you lie. Whether the world teaches children to speak or whether children are born to speak
别人不会看得起你 说真话会被伤害 说谎话却能获得信任 究竟是这世界教会了孩子说话 还是孩子天生就会说话
When Frank wants to leave again, Carl says that there is no one after you anymore. In the movie, his father always teaches Frank to keep messing with your life like a second mouse
当弗兰克再次想要离开时 卡尔说 你后面已经没有人在追你了 电影中 父亲一直教导弗兰克要像第二只老鼠那样不断的折腾你的人生
But the rebellious nonsense in his youth was because he knew there were a pair of eyes behind him. When the eyes were not his nonsense, his torment and who to see. He grew up, he was tired of torment
可年少时的叛逆胡闹 那是因为他知道后面有一双眼睛 当那双眼睛不在了 他的胡闹 他的折腾又给谁看呢 他长大了 他也折腾累了
Perhaps the greatest sadness for young Frank is that he had a place to learn all the professional knowledge but no place to learn how to be a human being
对于年少的弗兰克来说 或许最大的悲哀就在于他有地方学习所有的专业知识 却没地方学习怎么做人
Ok, that's all for today's commentary. Don't forget to follow the retweet and see you next time
好了 今天的解说就到这里了 喜欢的话别忘了关注转发哦 我们下期见